A Guide to the Robert Bolling Lambeth papers, 1921-2007
Library of Virginia
- Series III: Personal Papers., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 11-15)
  - Why Support Roosevelt by Bolling Lambeth, 1936. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - The Little Congress of the University of Virginia (orginally published in University of Virginia Alumni News May 1937), 1937. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Jefferson's Country co-written by Bolling Lambeth, 1937. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Articles by Robert Bolling Lambeth, 1936-1951. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Bedford, the No-Tax Town by Robert Bolling Lambeth in The Commonwealth, May 1938. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Review of Halifacts and related correspondence, 1941-1942. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Who is Ross Valentine? (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Poems by Robert Bolling Lambeth. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Public relations--general. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Pony. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Dogs, 1948-1984. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Notes. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Calendar, 1962. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Calendar-yearbook, 1963. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Photographs--house and mausoleum[?]. (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Festivals., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 15-16)
  Festivals contains articles, brochures, cards, cartoons, clippings, correspondence, memorabilia, pamphlets, photographs, programs, stationery, and other papers regarding the National Peanut Festival (Suffolk, Virginia), the National Seafood Festival (Hampton, Virginia), and the National Tobacco Festival (South Boston, Virginia).
  - National Peanut Festival papers, 1940-1942. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Brochures, cards, cartoon, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - National Peanut Festival photographs, 1941. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - National Seafood Festival program, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - National Seafood Festival seafood cook book, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - National Seafood Festival papers, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - National Seafood Festival photographs, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - National Seafood Festival photographs, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - National Seafood Festival photographs, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - National Seafood Festival photographs, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - National Seafood Festival photographs, 1948. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - National Seafood Festival photographs, 194. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - National Seafood Festival schedules, 1948-1949. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - National Seafood Festival clippings, 1948-1949. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - National Seafood Festival program, 1949. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - National Tobacco Festival program, 1937. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - National Tobacco Festival program, 1938. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - National Tobacco Festival articles and pamphlets, 1940. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - National Tobacco Festival, Inc., blank stationery, 1940. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - National Tobacco Festival historical guide, 1940. (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - National Tobacco Festival correspondence, 1940-1941. (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Series V: Law, commerce, and economics., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 16-20)
  Law, commerce and economics contains articles, booklets, books, magazines, newsletters, reports, and other papers concerning the law, finances, and economics of the United States and Virginia.
  - Annual reports of the Virginia State Bar, 1961-1962. (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Annual reports of the Virginia State Bar, 1963-1964. (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Bar News, December 1956. (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Virginia Bar News, July, September 1964. (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Federal Reporter: Reporting the Opinions of the U.S. Courts of Appeals, U.S. Court of Customs and Patent Appeals, and U.S. Emergency Court of Appeals, 16 January 1950. Corbin v. County School Board of Pulaski County, 4th Circuit Court of Appeals, equality of schools. (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Southeastern Reporter: Cases Decided in the Supreme Court of Appeals of Virginia, 11 July 1963, 16 July 1964. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Case and Comment, 1962-1963. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Case and Comment, 1964-1965. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Lawyers Title News, September-October 1977. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Lawyer, December 1997. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Opinion of Brockenbrough Lamb, Chancery Court of the City of Richmond, in Linton M. Dew v. First and Merchants National Bank, 11946. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Laws of Virginia Relating to Banking and Finance, 1970. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - More Letters from a Country Lawyer and Still More Letters from a Country Lawyer by Sam Hill (June Blackwell), ca. 1959-1962. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - The National Economy in Time of Crisis: Its Meaning to Lawyers and Their Clients--New Jersey State Bar Association, 1951. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Right of Way: a Guide for Property Owners and Tenants--Virginia Department of Transportation 1989. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Landlord/Tenant Handbook,--Office of Housing Assistance, Division of Housing, Virginia Department of Housing and Community Development, 1989. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, judges and courts, ca. 1950s. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - 8th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary--Estate Planning--a Case Study, 1962. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - 9th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, 1963. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - 10th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, 1964. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - 11th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, 1965. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - 12th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, 1966. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 13th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, 1967. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 14th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 15th Annual Tax Conference, Marshall-Wythe School of Law, College of William and Mary, 1969. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - National City Bank of New York [Monthly Newsletter on] Economic Conditions, Governmental Finance, United States Securities, June 1938. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Economic Conditions, Government Finance, December 1951. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Economic Conditions, Government Finance, February, April-May, July, October-December 1953. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, 1954. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, 1955 (Becomes First National City Bank of New York with April 1955 newsletter). (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, 1956. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, 1957. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, January-November 1958. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, January-April, June, August-September, November-December 1959 (includes April supplement letter). (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, 1960. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, January-February, April-May, September-December 1961. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Newsletter on Business and Economic Conditions, January, April, June-November 1962 (title becomes Monthly Economic Letter in July 1962). (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January-February, April-July, September-December 1963. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January, April-May, July, September-December 1965. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January-May, September-December 1966. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January-June, August-December 1967. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, February-December 1968. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, February-December 1969. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January, March-December 1970. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January-August 1971. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, July-August, October, December 1972. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January-March, May, August 1973. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, January-March, June-December 1974. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - First National City Bank of New York Monthly Economic Newsletter, February, April-May 1975. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Economic Review, April 1949, January, April, July 1950. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Virginia economic information, 1950-1951. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - A Guide to the Balance of Payments of the United States--Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, April 1961. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Farm Economics--Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology, Virginia Tech, Virginia Agricultural Extension Services, 1962-1967. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Tax Memos--First National Exchange Bank, 1966-1969. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, Virginia finances, ca. 1940-1941. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, economic development, 1952-1953. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, finance, 1954, no date. (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Politics., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 20-23)
  Politics contains publications, mainly from the Virginia Commission for Constitutional Government and the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, concerning politics and government at the state, national, and global levels.
  - The Civil Rights Bill (full text)--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government, April 1964. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - The Civil Rights Cases--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government, 1963. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Civil Rights and Federal Power--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights and Legal Wrongs--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Equality v. Liberty: The Eternal Conflict--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government, 1960. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - The Full Faith and Credit Clause of the United States Constitution Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - ...Nor Cruel and Unusual Punishment Inflicted: A Few Observations on the Meaning of the Eighth Amendment--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government, 1965. (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - One Man One Vote: A Presentation of Comments and Documentary Material Relating to the Supreme Court's Reapportionment Decision of June 15, 1964--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government, 1965. (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Reapportionment--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Reform the Electoral College: Some New Looks at an Old Institution--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - The Right Not to Listen--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government, 1964. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Sex, the Supreme Court, and the States--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Sockdolager! A Tale of Davy Crockett--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - State Action and the 14th Amendment--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The Supreme Court of the United States: A Review of the 1964 Term--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - The Tennessee Reapportionment Case--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Voting Rights and Legal Wrongs--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - When Virginia Joined the Union--Virginia Commission on Constitutional Government, 1963. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Civil Disobedience and Civilization, Industrial Society, and Love--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1966, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Consumers of Abundance and The Elite and the Electorate: Is Government by the People Possible?--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1961, 1963. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Ethics and the Politician and Fair Trial vs. A Free Press--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1960, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - First Things First and Government and Business in International Trade--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1964, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Mass Communications With a View of Our Press by 14 Foreign Journalists and a Discussion by Center Staff Members and The Negro as an American--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1966, 1963. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - The Politics of Ecology and The Quantitative Society or What Are You to Do With Noodle--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1966, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - The U.S. and Revolution--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - The U.S., Cuba, and Latin America and World Ecomonic Disparities--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the Free Society, 1961, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Segregation, Subsidies, and Megalopolis--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper on the City, 1964. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - On Coexistence and On the Developed and the Developing--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Occasional Paper from an International Convocation on Requirements of Peace, 1965, 1965. (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - A Conversation, Interview: The Police, Interview: The City, and Interview: The Law--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, The American Character, 1962 (all). (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Interview: Opinion Polls, Interview: Television, Interview: The Press, and Interview: Science--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, The American Character, 1961 and 1962. (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - The Economy Under Law, The Eichman Trial and the Rule of Law, and Permanent Peace--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Discussion of the Free Society, 1960, 1961, 1961. (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Politics and Ethics, Religion and American Society, and Religion and American Society--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Discussion of the Free Society, 1961 (all). (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Two Faces of Federalism and U.S. Foreign Policy and the Soviet Union--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Discussion of the Free Society, 1961 (both). (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - A World Without War, The Bill of Rights and the States, and Community of Fear--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Discussion of the Free Society, 1961, 1961, 1960. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - A Constitution for the World and Keeping the World Disarmed--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Papers on Peace, 1965 (both). (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - The Demilitarized World, To Live as Men: an Anatomy of Peace, and ...Therefore Choose Life--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Papers on Peace, 1964, 1965, 1965. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Dead Horse and the Featherbird, Our Own Kind: Voting by Race, Creed, or National Origin, and Democracy and Public Review--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Report, 1962, 1960, 1960. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Government of Science, Cybernation: the Silent Conquest, and Rediscovering Natural Law--Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Report, 1962 (all). (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - The Power of Reason,--special report by Robert M. Hutchins, President of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Saturday Review, When the World Talked Peace: Highlights of the Pacem in Terris Convocation sponsored by the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1965. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Feel Free: The Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, speech by Senator Thomas H. Kuchel (R-California), 26 February 1964. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - The Art of Government, by James Reichley, report for the Fund for the Republic, 1959. (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Series VII: Planning., Extent: 1 box. (Box 23)
  Planning contains booklets, magazines, newsletters, reports, and other papers regarding community, industrial, and regional planning in Virginia.
  - Citizens' Planning Guide: You Can Help Plan Your Community--Appalachian Power Company. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Fire Protection: Present and Future Needs--Northern Virginia Regional Planning and Economic Development Commission, 1962. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Forward--Virginia Division of Industrial Development and Planning, July 1964, January 1965. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Mr. Planning Commissioner--Public Administrative Service, 1954. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Planning Legislation--Virginia Division of Industrial Development and Planning, Department of Conservation and Ecomonic Development, 1961. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Population in Central Virginia--Central Virginia Planning Commission, April 1976. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Preparing for the Prospect--Virginia Division of Industrial Development and Planning, 1962. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Public Land and Facilties--Northern Virginai Regional Planning and Economic Development Commission, September 1962. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Virginia's Common Wealth--Citizens' Committee for the Virginia Outdoors Plan. (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Series VIII: Education., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 23-24)
  Education consists of articles, clippings, correspondence, memorandums, minutes, reports, and other papers concerning education and schools in Bedford County (specifically New London Academy), Virginia, and the United States.
  - New London Academy papers, 1984. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - New London Academy, 1985-1986. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - New London Academy, undated. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - New London Academy correspondence from George E. Nolley, superintendent of schools (Campbell County), 27 June 1985. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - New London Academy clippings, 1984-1985. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Six School Structures, Bedford County, Virginia: Architectural, Mechanical, Electrical, and Structural Analysis, 1983. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Educational Needs and Building Requirements for White Students in Bedford County, Virginia Prepared for the School Board of Bedford County, Virginia, 1958. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, education--Bedford County, 1951, undated. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Schools--Virginia and Bedford County, 1950-1952, undated. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Clippings--education, 1947, 1950-1951, undated. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Southern Schools: Progress and Problems--Southern Education Reporting Service, 1959. (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Series IX: UVA magazines and newsletters., Extent: 1 box. (Box 24)
  UVA magazines and newsletters detail various aspects of the University of Virginia, including education, operations, and alumni relations; as well discuss state and national politics and culture. Some issues contain articles written by Robert Bolling Lambeth.
  - University of Virginia Magazine--Practice in Politics, pages 15-16, December 1936. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - University of Virginia Alumni News--The Little Congress of the University of Virginia, pages 189-190,204, May 1937. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - University of Virginia Alumni News, May-June, July-August, November-December 1966. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - University of Virginia Alumni News, January-February, March-April 1967. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - University of Virginia Newsletter, 1962-1964. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - University of Virginia Newsletter, 1965-1967. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - University of Virginia Newsletter, 1968-1970. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - University of Virginia Newsletter, 1971-1974. (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Series X: Chamber of Commerce., Extent: 1 box. (Box 24)
  Chamber of Commerce contains magazines and publications highlighting the operations and activities of both the national and Virginia state chambers. Some issues contain articles written by Robert Bolling Lambeth.
  - Proposed Policy Decisions to Be Voted on at the 39th Annual Meeting of the National Chamber, 30 April-2 May 1951. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - The Commonwealth--Conference on World Peace pages 22-23, June 1937. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - The Commonwealth--Bedford, the No-Tax Town pages 15-16, May 1938. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Journal of American Chamber of Commerce Executives, July, October 1952. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Journal of American Chamber of Commerce Executives, January, April 1953. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Journal of American Chamber of Commerce Executives, July, October 1953. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - The New Dominion--published by the Virginia State Junior Chamber of Commerce, September 1948, March 1950. (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Series XI: General publications., Extent: 1 box. (Box 25)
  General publications contains articles, booklets, magazines, and newsletters on topics ranging from politics and foreign policty, economy, and human behavior to rivers and water conservation; from Norfolk and Hampton Roads, Virginia, and Tucson, Arizona, to public affairs and museums. Also includes reminiscences of Charles E. Burks and W. B. Barbour.
  - Our Most Precious Freedom by Sam J. Ervin in The American Legion, March 1985. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - The Blue Book of Southern Progress, 1951. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Career Exploration: unit 1--4-H and Virginia Tech Agricultural Extension Service, February 1962. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - The Definition of an Intoxicating Beverage--reprint from Quarterly Journal of Studies on Alcohol, June 1955. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Democratic Digest, November-December 1958. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Editor and Publisher: the Fourth Estate, 1948. (Box 25, Folder 6)